JOSH BOOKER

Contact Information:

+447956716836

josh.booker2@gmail.com

https://github.com/ JoshNBooker

www.linkedin.com/in/joshbooker

14/3 Brunswick Road Edinburgh, EH7 5NQ

Skills:

- Javascript
- · Typescript
- Java
- PHP
- · Wordpress
- jQuery
- React
- Python
- CSS3
- HTML5

I am a Junior Software Developer specialising in Javascript, Typescript, React, CSS3 and HTML5. I have a keen eye for creative, responsive and fun design, and would love to build these skills in a supportive work environment. Continuously challenging myself and evolving my technical skills and knowledge is something I am relentlessly passionate about. I have collaborated on extensive projects as part of a team, as well as produced high-caliber work of my own. My varied background has also given me excellent skills such as communication, teaching and mentoring, and presenting.

Key Achievements:

Built a portfolio website which is currently hosted through Vercel. This was
made using Typescript, React and additional libraries. It features a
development blog that is pulled in through a REST API, the back-end of which
is hosted on dev.to.

https://portfolio-josh-vert.vercel.app

 Created an interactive and note taking app based on the idea of a virtual cork board. This implemented Typescript, Java, Spring Boot and various React Libraries to let users fully customise their themes.

https://github.com/JoshNBooker/note_taking_app

 Built an interactive location-based walking ghost tour app with React Native, React Native maps, Spring Boot, Leaflet and Java. I primarily worked on building the user interface and location the location tracking functionality. I also set up the backend and handled pulling in data through the API.

https://github.com/JoshNBooker/spook city app

 Collaborated on building a React based browser game, with a tech stack of React, Express and MongoDB. With this project, I developed the backend and lead design and structure decisions. In addition, I developed the Javascript interactivity features.

https://github.com/Blair4932/GitBash

• Built a solo Flask app, utilising Python, Jinja, Postico, HTML and CSS. This was a solo project and I handled all of the aspects of this project.

https://github.com/JoshNBooker/Sakura Spa booking app

EXPERIENCE

Client Service Advisor

Vegware Ltd. - Edinburgh, UK November 2021 - July 2023

- · Resolved a huge variety of customer queries, utilising a range of systems and processes.
- Provided introductory training to new staff as well as advanced training to existing staff on new technologies.
- Tested and improved AI based order processing systems, workflow management systems and order related databases.
- Represented Vegware to high-level stakeholders and clients as their account manager within the order processing team.
- Led a project to improve processes, website interactions, and automated correspondence from a customer experience perspective.

Client Service Advisor

Lloyds Banking Group - Edinburgh, UK June 2020-November 2021

- · Provided support to highly valued stakeholders.
- · Provided coaching to less experience team members.
- Identified improvements to new and existing processes, procedures, and systems.
- Was the key member of staff for resolving difficult and ongoing client queries.

Teacher - English as a Second Language

Mackenzie School of English - Edinburgh, UK January 2019 - April 2020

- Taught English to students in one-to-one and large group settings.
- · Supported students and worked with them to set goals and come up with personal development plans.
- Evaluated student progress and wrote reports on their course development.
- Worked with other teachers and staff to ensure course delivery and student experience was always to the highest quality.
- · Created innovative lessons that were added to the school's permanent rotation of lesson plans.

Teacher - English as a Second Language

Universidad Del Istmo — Oaxaca, Mexico April 2018 - November 2018

- Taught English to university students (pre-intermediate to advanced levels).
- Provided one-to-one support to all students and met with them individually to set goals and assess progress.
- Developed the course syllabus, content, activities, and examinations.
- Provided specialist English support to professors, translated documents, assisted in the publication of academic papers by editing and proofreading texts to an extremely high standard.

EDUCATION

Professional Software Developer Course

CodeClan August 2023 - October 2023

PDA Software Development SCQF levels 8 and 9

CodeClan August 2023 - November 2023

Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages

Trinity College London November 2017 - December 2017

MA Creative Writing (Pass with Honours)

Nottingham Trent University September 2016 - December 2016

BA Film and Television / Communication and Society Joint Hons (2.1)

Nottingham Trent University September 2013 - September 2012

VOLUNTEERING

Co-founder and Community Event Organiser

- Chuun Edinburgh, Scotland
 October 2021 Present
- Build partnerships and develop relationships with local charitable organisations, venues, groups, musicians, and artists in Edinburgh.
- Organise events and work with members of the community to promote community action and support local causes
- Editor of Chuun's regular poetry and literature zine

LANGUAGES

• English (native); Spanish (intermediate)

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.